Guide to the Atwater Family Papers, 1788 - 2003
Atwater Family Papers, 1788 - 2003
- Series V. Charles Woodard Atwater, 1892-1948, 2 linear feet
  - Correspondence
    - Charles Woodard Atwater - Alice Caroline Merriam Atwater, 1907 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - 1908 Jan (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - 1908 Jan-Feb (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - 1908 Feb (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - 1908 Feb (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - 1908 Mar (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - 1908 Mar (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - 1908 Mar-Apr (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - 1908 Jul-Dec (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - 1909 Apr (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - 1909 Apr-May (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - 1909 May (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - 1909 May-Jun (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - 1909 Jun (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - 1910 Aug (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - 1911 Jan (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - 1911 Jan (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - 1911 Jan (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - 1911 Jan (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - 1911 Feb (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Charles Woodard Atwater - Alice Caroline Merriam, 1911 Feb (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - 1911 Feb-Mar (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Charles Woodard Atwater - Helen Woodard Atwater, 1899-1909 (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - 1924-1927 (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - 1929 (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - 1930 Jan-Dec (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - 1931 Jan-Sep (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - 1932 Jan-Dec (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - 1933 Jan-Dec (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - 1934-1941 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Undated (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Charles Woodard Atwater - Marcia Woodard Atwater, 1899 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - 1908 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - 1909 Jan-Feb (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - 1909 Mar-Oct (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - 1918-1920 (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Charles Woodard Atwater - Wilbur Olin Atwater, 1891-1903 (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - Charles Woodard Atwater - Others, 1897-1899 (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - 1901 (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - 1902 (Box 19, Folder 15)
    - 1906 Jun-Jul (Box 19, Folder 16)
    - 1907 Aug-Sep (Box 19, Folder 16)
    - Charles Woodard Atwater: condolence letters, 1907 Sep (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Charles Woodard Atwater: condolence letters, 1907 Oct (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Charles Woodard Atwater - Others, 1907 Oct (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - 1907 Nov (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - 1907 Nov (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - 1907 Dec (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Charles Woodard Atwater - Others, 1907 Dec (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - 1911-1938, Undated (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Personal Papers
    - School papers, 1892-1902 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous papers, 1901-1909 (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - "So Far It's Just A Dream" article by Charles Woodard Atwater in Collier's, 1924 Aug 2 (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - Banquet program: "We" Banquet in Honor of Captain Charles A. Lindbergh, 1927 Jun 14 (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - Banquet program: Banquet in honor of the Commander and Crew Of the "America", Commander Richard E. Byrd, 1927 Jul 19 (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - Banquet program: Banquet in Honor of Captain Hermann Koehl, Major James Fitzmaurice, and Baron Guenther von Huenefeld, 1928 Apr 28 (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - Manuscript writings Charles W. Atwater, 1928-1938, Undated (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - Cemetery memorials, 1948 (Box 20, Folder 16)
- Series VI. Alice Caroline Merriam Atwater, 1905-1950, .5 linear feet
  Contains letters from Alice Merriam to Charles Atwater, most written before their marriage. She describes her social life at Smith College and then in Middletown. There is a small amount of correspondence with others.
  - Alice Caroline Merriam - Charles Woodard Atwater, 1905 Oct-Dec (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - 1906 Jan-Feb (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - 1906 Feb-Mar (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - 1906 Mar-Jun (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - 1907 Sep (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - 1907 Oct (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - 1907 Oct (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - 1907 Nov (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - 1907 Nov (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - 1907 Dec (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Alice Caroline Merriam - Others, 1907-1948 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Nassau County, Office of Civilian Protection identification card, Undated (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Funeral program for Alice Caroline Merriam Atwater, 1950 May (Box 21, Folder 13)
- Series VII. Catherine Merriam Atwater Galbraith, 1940-1994, 1 linear foot
  Contains mostly correspondence between Catherine, sometimes "Kitty", and her brother Robert. Catherine's letters to her brother, Charles Woodard Atwater, Jr. are in Series VIII. There is some correspondence in this series relating to their brother's care and condition, settling their mother's estate, the challenges of growing children and later challenges of caring for a disabled spouse. The series also includes Catherine's articles, correspondence, and research notes on her family history of William Warren Atwater and Wilbur Olin Atwater.
  - Correspondence
    - Catherine Merriam Atwater Galbraith - Robert Merriam Atwater, 1940-1953 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence re: family matters, 1947-1953 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - General correspondence, 1960-1963 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Catherine Merriam Atwater Galbraith - Robert Merriam Atwater, 1960-1964 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Wesleyan University/Wyman Parker, 1966-1967 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Research interest in Atwater family papers, 1967, 1971 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Catherine Merriam Atwater Galbraith - Robert Merriam Atwater, 1991-1992 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Catherine Merriam Atwater Galbraith - Robert Merriam Atwater, 1992-1993 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Atwater Centennial, 1992-1994 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Family correspondence, undated (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Personal Papers
    - Writings on Wilbur Olin Atwater, 1994 (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Research materials on Wilbur Olin Atwater, undated (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - Writing on William Warren Atwater, 1991 (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - Research materials on William Warren Atwater, undated (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence relating to research and writing, 1990-1994 (Box 22, Folder 15)
    - Helen Woodard Atwater's address book, 1929 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Bank books related to Helen's estate, 1946-1948 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Wall Street Journal issue, 1947 Jun 26 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Financial Papers, 1947-1948 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Financial Papers, 1947-1948 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - The Yacht - Duckling, 1990s (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Notebook - research notes, undated (Box 23, Folder 7)
- Series VIII. Charles Atwater, 1933-2002, 3 linear feet
  Contains his correspondence and papers. Charles' letters describe his work as a farm hand prior to college and during vacations, his service experience as Pharmacist's Mate, and his deepening interest in foreign policy immediately following his military service. Most of the incoming letters from family members have news of children, travel, and house; a small portion touches on his mental health and care. His sister's letters to aunts or cousins are located in this series as enclosures with their letters to Charles. More family correspondence concerning his health and care is found in Series VII in letters between his siblings Catherine Atwater Galbraith and Robert Atwater. The correspondence is arranged chronologically, the personal papers are arranged alphabetically by topic.
  - Correspondence
    - 1936 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - 1937 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - 1938 Jan-Jul (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - 1938 Aug-Dec (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - 1939 Jan-Jul (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - 1939 Aug-Dec (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - 1939-1942 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - 1940 (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - 1941 (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - 1942 Jan-Apr (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - 1942 May-Dec (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - 1943 Jan-Apr (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - 1943 May (Box 24, Folder 13)
    - 1943 Jun (Box 24, Folder 14)
    - 1943 Jul-Dec (Box 24, Folder 15)
    - 1944 (Box 24, Folder 16)
    - Envelopes without contents, 1943-1944 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Attachments separated from letters, 1943-1944 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - 1945 Jan-Apr (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - 1945 May-Aug (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - 1945 Sep-Dec (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - 1946 Jan-May (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - 1946 Jun-Oct (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - 1946 Nov-Dec (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - 1947 Jan-Feb (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - 1947 Mar-Jul (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - 1947 Aug-Dec (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - 1948 Jan-May (Box 25, Folder 12)
    - 1948 Jun-Dec (Box 25, Folder 13)
    - 1949 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - 1950-1956 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - 1957 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - 1958 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - 1959 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - 1960-1962 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - 1963 (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - 1964 (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - 1965 (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - 1966 (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - 1967 (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - 1968 (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - 1969 (Box 26, Folder 13)
    - 1970 (Box 26, Folder 14)
    - 1971 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - 1972 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - 1973 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - 1974 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - 1975 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - 1976 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - 1977 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - 1978 (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - 1979 (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - 1980 (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - 1981 (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - 1982 (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - 1983 (Box 27, Folder 13)
    - 1984 (Box 27, Folder 14)
    - 1985 (Box 27, Folder 15)
    - 1986 (Box 27, Folder 16)
    - 1987 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - 1988 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - 1989 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - 1990 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - 1991 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - 1992 (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - 1993 (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - 1994 (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - 1995 (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - 1996 (Box 28, Folder 10)
    - 1997 (Box 28, Folder 11)
    - 1998-1999 (Box 28, Folder 12)
    - 1990-1999 (Box 28, Folder 13)
    - 2000, 2002 (Box 28, Folder 14)
    - undated (Box 28, Folder 15)
    - undated (Box 28, Folder 16)
    - undated (Box 28, Folder 17)
  - Personal Papers
    - Boy Scouts of America membership card, 1933 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Calendar, 1993-1995 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Caricature, undated (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Coast Guard, 1942-1949 (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Coast Guard, 1942-1949 (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Cornell Alumni, 1942-1948 (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Cuba souvenir booklets, circa 1943 (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - Education Iowa State College transcript, 1949 (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - Education Cornell University, 1941-1942 (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - Education Manhasset High School, 1936-1937 (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - Education Smith College transcript1949 (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - Educational materials, reading lists, circa 1940-1949 (Box 29, Folder 12)
    - Job searches, circa 1942-1958 (Box 29, Folder 13)
    - Legal papers, 1947-1952 (Box 29, Folder 14)
    - Memberships, 1942-1951 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Memorial service: arrangements, condolences, 2003 (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - Memorial service guest book, 2003 (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous: driver's license, graduate record exam, 1946-1948 (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Notes, 1947, undated (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - Prescriptions, 1945-1964 (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - Receipts, 1942-1979 (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - Student Federalists, 1947 (Box 30, Folder 8)
- Series IX. Atwater family, 1874 and undated, .25 linear feet
  Contains miscellaneous items relating to the Atwater family as a whole (rather than individual family members).
  - Calling cards and addresses, undated (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Engraving plates (3), 1874 (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Atwater family genealogy (photocopy), undated (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous notes, undated (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - Print: Race Week at Manhasset Bay, Port Washington, L.I. mounted on wood, undated (Box 30, Folder 13)
- Series X. Merriam family, 1844-1955, .5 linear feet
  Contains miscellaneous items relating to the Merriam family as a whole (rather than individual family members). The series includes the postcard collection started by Mrs. Joseph Merriam and added to by family members. The postcards include American and European sites; some cards were sent by family members and friends.
  - Merriam family history, undated (Box 30, Folder 14)
  - Merriam family history, undated (Box 30, Folder 15)
  - J. Merriam letter to "Woggie", 1913 Jul 24 (Box 30, Folder 16)
  - Joseph Merriam Estate, 1945-1947 (Box 30, Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous notes, 1844-1955 (Box 30, Folder 18)
  - Postcard collection, 1911-1959 (Box 31)
- Series XI. Photographs, 1850-1999, .5 linear feet
  Includes individual portrait photographs of Atwater, Woodard and Merriam family members. There are also some family group portraits and events, as well as few casual photographs of family members and their interests. There are photographs of Wilbur Olin Atwater's laboratory and his annotations on photographs from his 1903 trip to Europe. The photographs are organized by family member; family small group photographs are filed with the older generation (i.e. grandmother and granddaughter filed with the grandmother).
  - William Warren Atwater, Sarah Fuller Atwater, circa 1860, 1875 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Wilbur Olin Atwater, circa 1850-1880 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Wilbur Olin Atwater, circa 1890-1900 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Wilbur Olin Atwater at New Brunswick, Canada camp, circa 1900 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Wilbur Olin Atwater, Monta Rosa, Italy, laboratory and scenes, 1903? (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Wilbur Olin Atwater University of Upsala, Sweden; Finland; Mt. Blanc, 1897? (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Wilbur Olin Atwater's laboratory, Wilbur Olin Atwater in laboratory, circa 1900-1907 (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - House at Washington and High Streets, [227 Washington Street] Middletown, Conn., circa 1870-1900 (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - Helen Woodard Atwater, circa 1876-1900 (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - Helen Woodard Atwater with family, circa 1916-1946 (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - Marcia Woodard Atwater, circa 1853-1875 (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - Marcia Woodard Atwater with family, circa 1916-1946 (Box 32, Folder 12)
  - Charles Woodard Atwater, 1885-1900 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Charles Woodard Atwater with Alice Caroline Merriam Atwater, with family, circa 1913-1940 (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Charles Woodard Atwater Duckling, Duckling crew, houseboat, circa 1917-1930 (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Charles Woodard Atwater, King Pradajhipok, and Queen Rambai Barni of Siam (Thailand), 1941 (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Alice Caroline Merriam Atwater, 1888-1898 (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Alice Caroline Merriam Atwater, 1900-1905 (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Alice Caroline Merriam Atwater, 1905-1913 (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Alice Caroline Merriam Atwater, 1907-1908 (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - Alice Caroline Merriam Atwater, circa 1909-1945 (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - Alice Caroline Merriam Atwater, Bermuda, undated (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - Catherine Atwater Galbraith with family, family members, circa 1915-2000 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Robert Merriam Atwater, circa 1916-1976 (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Charles Woodard Atwater, Jr., circa 1925-1947 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Charles Woodard Atwater, Jr., circa 1942-1950 (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Charles Woodard Atwater, Jr., circa 1970-1999 (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Charles Woodard Atwater, Jr., USS Spar, Ames, Iowa YMCA residents, circa 1942-1947 (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - USS Spar, undated (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - Charles Woodard Atwater, Jr. Fiji people and views (16 items), circa 1940-1950 (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - Merriam family, 1930-1959 (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - Joseph Merriam, circa 1874-1880 (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - Joseph Merriam, circa 1910-1945 (Box 34, Folder 11)
  - Joseph Merriam, 1912 (Box 34, Folder 12)
  - Joseph Merriam, Photograph Christmas cards, 1901-1941 (Box 34, Folder 13)
  - Frances Abigail Wilson Merriam with family, 1910-1915 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Margaret Eleanor Merriam Cornell Parsons, circa 1915-1928 (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Margaret Eleanor Merriam Cornell Parsons, circa 1915-1928 (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Helen Merriam Parsons, circa 1903-1960 (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Robert Merriam, 1930? (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - Atwater and Woodard family friends (carte-de-visite): (Box 35, Folder 6)
    Annie W. Bingham, undated
    W. H. Burnett, undated
    Macie D?, Vergennes, VT, 1865
    Mary Green, Vergennes, VT, undated
    Frances Hine, Colchester, VT, 1864
    Hattie Hine, Colchester, VT, undated
    Louise Hine, Colchester, VT, undated
    Louise Judd, Vergennes, VT, 1865
    Frau Peschka-Leubrier, undated
    G. W. Shearer, Crown Point, undated
    Mrs. M. Doane Willard, Vergennes, VT, 1868
    Nellie Wright, Spencer, Mass., undated
    Marcia Atwater, Fannie Greene, Mollie Greene,
    Dorrine Smith, Anna Tucker, 1867 Sep 12
    Mollie Hubbard, Laurie Smith, Anna Tucker,
    Doane Willard Vergennes, VT, 1867 Jul 21
  - Atwater and Woodard family unidentified friends (carte-de-visite) (12 men and women), 1860-1887 (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - Atwater baby, 1920? (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Charles Woodard Atwater, circa 1904-1930 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Charles Woodard Atwater Duckling, three-mast ship, undated (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Charles Woodard Atwater, Jr., circa 1942-1946 (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Charles Woodard Atwater, Jr., circa 1942-1946 (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Charles Woodard Atwater, Jr., circa 1942-1946 (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Wilbur Olin Atwater and Marcia Woodard Atwater (cased ambrotype, front cover detached), circa 1855 (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - Mother and child, seated (Atwater? Merriam?)(cased ambrotype, faded), circa 1850-1860 (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Atwater family, 1928 Apr 30 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Wilbur Olin Atwater house at Washington and High Streets, Middletown, Conn. [227 Washington Street], undated (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Charles Woodard Atwater, circa 1906-1920 (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Charles Woodard Atwater, Jr., Circa 1942-1945 (Box 37, Folder 4)
- Series XII. Printed materials, 1901-1994, 1.5 linear feet
  Contains printed and published material by, about, or owned by the Atwater family. Their recreational and occupational interests are represented. The series is organized in two loose alphabetical sequences.
  - "The Ancient History of Boron Deficiency", Journal of the American Society of Agronomy reprint, 1941 Oct (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - "The Duckling's Cruise to Ireland" The New England Yachtsman, undated (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Fullbright exhibit program, 1982 Jun (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - "Helen Woodard Atwater-A Tribute", Journal of Home Economics, 1947 Sep (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Newspaper clippings, circa 1900-1977 (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - Pamphlets, brochures, leaflets, 1891-1907 (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - Pamphlets, programs Smith College, 1907-1910 (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - Public Affairs Pamphlet No. 72, "When Mental Illness Strikes Your Family", 1951 (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - Storrs Agricultural Experiment Station, Dedication of Atwater Laboratory (2 copies), 1930 Jun 30 (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - USDA (newsletter), 1944 Apr 1 (Box 38, Folder 10)
  - U.S. Naval Institute Proceedings, 1976 Mar (Box 38, Folder 11)
  - Wilbur Olin Atwater: Gin and the Perils of Pure Research (in Black and Red), undated (Box 38, Folder 12)
  - Wilbur Olin Atwater Memorial Lecture, 1968, 1970, 1971 (Box 38, Folder 13)
  - Wilbur Olin Atwater Centennial Celebration Symposium, 1993 Jun 2-4 (Box 38, Folder 14)
  - "Wilbur Olin Atwater Father of American Nutrition" Science Agricultural Research, 1993 Jan (Box 38, Folder 15)
  - Wilbur Olin Atwater CAG manuscript for Journal of Nutrition, 1994 (Box 38, Folder 16)
  - A World Law Bureau Cornell Law Quarterly, 1929 Dec (Box 38, Folder 17)
  - "William Warren Atwater: Minister, Publisher, and Crusader Against Rum" by Catherine Atwater Galbraith, undated (Box 38, Folder 18)
  - Ulisse 2000. Alitalia, 1955 Oct (Box 38, Folder 19)
  - Zingara's 1920 Cruise, circa 1920 (Box 38, Folder 20)
  - Atwater History and Genealogy. Compiled by Francis Atwater. Meriden, Conn.: The Journal Printing Company, 1901 (Box 39)
  - Connecticut Agricultural College: A History. Walter Stemmons New Haven, Conn.: Tuttle, Morehouse & Taylor, Company, 1931 (Box 39)
  - Memoirs of Francis Atwater … Francis Atwater. Meriden, Conn.: Horton Printing Company, 1865 (Box 39)
  - The Great Adventure 1496 to 1956: Atwater History and Genealogy. Charles Hobart Attwater. Santa Monica, Calif, 1956 (Box 39)
  - Alumni Record of Wesleyan University. Middletown, Conn. Edited by Frank W. Nicolson. New Haven, Conn.: Tuttle, Morehouse & Taylor, Company, 1911 (Box 40)
  - The Cornellian, 1942 (Box 40)
  - The Plandrome Story. Compiled by Clare Sutherland. n.p., 1965? (Box 40)
  - The Great Adventure 1496 to 1956: Atwater History and Genealogy. Charles Hobart Attwater. Santa Monica, Calif, 1956 (Box 40)
- Series XIII. Oversize materials, 1899-1957, 2 linear feet
  Contains items from other series that require large housing.
  - Joseph and Lucy Merriam family tree (photocopy on foam core), undated (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Wilbur Olin Atwater Marcia & Woodard Atwater marriage certificate, 1874 Aug 26 (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Wilbur Olin Atwater, Swedish Royal Academy of Agriculture Foreign Member diploma, 1897 Nov 15 (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Wilbur Olin Atwater, Imperial Academy of Military Medicine Corresponding Member certificates (one Russian, one French), 1899 Mar 31 (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Helen Woodard Atwater, Smith College honorary degree, 1943 May 20 (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - Charles Woodard Atwater, Connecticut District Court Clerk certificate, 1930 (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - Charles Woodard Atwater Jr., Nassau County Spelling Champion certificate, 1933 (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - Charles Woodard Atwater Jr., Graduating class U.S.C.G. Hospital Corps School of Pharmacy,Columbia. Photograph., 1942 Aug 15 (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - Charles Woodard Atwater Jr., Decorative pillow cover (20"x20") "South Seas 1946 To My Dear Mother", 1945 (Box 41, Folder 9)
  - Life, 1957 Oct 21 (Box 41, Folder 10)
  - Yachting, 1925, 1927 (Box 41, Folder 11)